https://www.rsna.org/about/rsna-privacy-policy

Advertisement
To help offer the best experience possible, RSNA uses cookies on its site. By browsing here, you acknowledge our terms of use. To find more information about our cookie policy visit
here.
OK
Find out more
To help offer the best experience possible, RSNA uses cookies on its site. By browsing here, you acknowledge our terms of use. To find more information about our cookie policy visit
here.
OK
Find out more
Search
News
About
Donate
Login
Membership
Renew membership
Continue to enjoy the benefits of your RSNA membership.
Annual Meeting
FAQs
Pricing and registration
Plenary and honorees
Fun run
Abstract submission
Future and past meetings
Exhibitor list and industry presentations
Education
Continuing medical education (CME)
AI resources and training
Imaging AI in Practice
AI challenge
Webinars
Professionalism and quality care
Professionalism self-assessments
Quality Improvement Certificate Program
Education awards
View workshops
Explore programs in grant writing, research development and academic radiology.
Research
Funding opportunities
Education Grants
Research grants
Application process FAQs
Grant writing resources
Research development guides
Imaging research tools
QIBA meetings
Quantitative Imaging Data Warehouse (QIDW)
View imaging research tools
Learn about tools to help radiologists work more efficiently.
Practice Tools
Quality Improvement
Quality Improvement Reports
Quality Improvement Resources
Patient-centered care
RSNA-ACR 3D Printing Registry
Protecting PHI in Presentations
Data tools and standards
RadReport reporting templates
RadElement common data elements
RadLex radiology lexicon
Image Share
Integrating the Healthcare Enterprise
RSNA Case Collection
Explore our library of cases to aid in diagnosis, submit your own or become a reviewer.
COVID-19
Back
COVID-19 Resources
Consensus statements and guidance
RSNA structured reporting
RICORD
RICORD resources
RICORD FAQs
Education
Continuing medical education (CME)
AI resources and training
Imaging AI in Practice
AI challenge
RSNA Pulmonary Embolism Detection Challenge (2020)
RSNA Intracranial Hemorrhage Detection Challenge (2019)
RSNA Pneumonia Detection Challenge (2018)
RSNA Pediatric Bone Age Challenge (2017)
Webinars
Professionalism and quality care
Professionalism self-assessments
Communicating bad news
Employing Humor in the Radiology Workplace
Professionalism for residents
Quality Improvement Certificate Program
Advanced level request form
Clinical Trials Methodology Workshop
RSNA/ASNR Comparative Effectiveness Research Training (CERT)
Creating and Optimizing the Research Enterprise (CORE)
Introduction to Academic Radiology
Introduction to Academic Radiology for Scientists (ITARSc)
Introduction to Research for International Young Academics
NIH Grantsmanship
Value of Imaging through Comparative Effectiveness Program (VOICE)
Writing a Competitive Grant Proposal
Research
Funding opportunities
Education Grants
Derek Harwood-Nash International Education Scholar Grant
Education Research Development Grant
Research grants
Medical Student Research Grant
QIBA meetings
Quantitative Imaging Data Warehouse (QIDW)
The Quantitative Imaging Data Warehouse (QIDW) Contributor Request
View imaging research tools
Practice Tools
Quality Improvement
Quality Improvement Reports
Quality Improvement Resources
Patient-centered care
Communication toolkit
Patient-centered care reading list
About RSNA
The Radiological Society of North America (hereafter, ‘RSNA’, ‘the Society’, ‘we’) is an international society of radiologists, medical physicists and other medical professionals with more than 54,000 members across the globe with the mission to promote excellence in patient care and health care delivery through education, research and technologic innovation.
RSNA was established in 1915 and hosts one of the world’s largest annual medical meetings, a week-long event which starts the last Sunday of November in Chicago. The Society also publishes peer-reviewed journals including Radiology, offering radiology research and reviews, and RadioGraphics, dedicated to continuing education in radiology.
The Society also develops and offers informatics-based software solutions support of a universal electronic health record, sponsors research to advance quantitative imaging biomarkers, and conducts outreach to enhance education in developing nations. Through its Research & Education (R&E) Foundation, RSNA provides millions of dollars in funding to investigators.
You can contact us at:
Radiological Society of North America
820 Jorie Boulevard
Suite 200
Oak Brook, Illinois 60523, USA
privacy@rsna.org
Telephone (U.S. and Canada): 1-800-381-6660
Telephone: 1-630-571-2670
For the purposes of European Union (EU) data protection law (in particular the General Data Protection Regulation, or “GDPR”, and its implementing laws at national level in the EU), we are controller of the processing of Personally Identifiable Information (PII), we describe in this Policy.
About this Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy details how we process PII, including the personal data of individuals residing in the EU and the European Economic Area (EEA) when they interact with our services.
In principle, RSNA:
Collects, uses and stores the minimum amount of personal data that is necessary for one or more legitimate business purposes and to comply with legal obligations.
Limits who has access to the personal data in our possession to only those who need it for legitimate business purposes.
Protects personal data through physical and technical security measures tailored to the sensitivity of the personal data we hold.
Communicates with our employees, customers, suppliers, business partners and others about how we intend to use personal data in our day-to-day operations.
Takes reasonable steps to ensure our personal data is accurate and up-to-date.
Integrates privacy in the design of our activities, the software we develop and projects that involve the use of personal data.
If you are based in the EU or the EEA and you are interacting with RSNA as a provider of services or goods, or us monitoring your behavior, then the related processing of your personal data is governed by the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and its implementing national laws.
Types of Information Collected
We recognize personal data as any information related to an identified or identifiable individual. Depending on the context of your interactions with RSNA, we collect and use different types of personal data from website visitors, members of our Society and others that interact with us.
Types of information we collect:
Membership information: when applying for an RSNA membership you will be asked to complete the appropriate form providing your contact and professional information. For certain positions you should also provide your photograph, bank details, and your authorization to verify your information with the appropriate licensing authorities or other relevant entities.
Accounts on our website: All members and customers have the possibility to create an online account. Besides the information you provide us when becoming a member, we also process your username, passwords, and we log your activity on the website.
Registration to events, conferences and the annual meeting: we organize different events and conferences, and usually require your contact details and financial details. Additional information may be required of registrants seeking additional services such as accommodation preferences.
Customer information: we work with a variety of nonprofit and commercial partners to support our mission through advertising and sponsorship at our Annual Meeting, in journals, and other activities and collect information from them in the course of our interaction.
Marketing activities: e-mail addresses and information about the interaction with our communications (such as IP addresses, opens, click-through data). We may also send surveys and collect various responses to these surveys which may include contact and professional information. RSNA uses this information to improve customer service, gather customer feedback and gauge interest in new products or services. RSNA also sends content provided by relevant commercial partners to interested members and meeting attendees.
Videos and photos: we collect and use videos and photos of members and event attendees in publicly available educational and promotional materials. Some of them include testimonies of persons who authorized us to share their personal experiences.
Mobile App: we have a mobile app “RSNA 20XX Meeting App” by EventPilot available to our annual meeting attendees that collects information including device ID, login credentials, content preferences, and social media profiles. The full privacy policy of the app is available here.
Submissions to our journals: we collect name, contact details, affiliation of authors that submit papers or reports to our journals. See our Cookies Policy for more information.
Information collected automatically: there is other information that we collect automatically when you visit our site through the use of cookies or similar technologies, such as your IP address, browser type, access times.
Fellowship application: when applying for an RSNA fellowship or funding you will be asked to complete the appropriate form providing your contact and professional information. For certain positions you should also provide your photograph, bank details, and your authorization to verify your information with the appropriate licensing authorities or other relevant entities.
Why we process your personal data
The purposes for which we collect and use your personal data may vary depending on the type of relationship you have with us, such as if you are one of our members or a website visitor.
See below how we use your information:
We process personal data collected through our annual meeting app for the purpose of helping attendees locate content of interest to them.
We process personal data of applicants to membership for the purpose of verifying their credentials to see if they meet the criteria to become members and for the purpose of processing the membership fee.
We process personal data of our members when they log into their online accounts for the purpose of managing their membership and providing them membership related services.
We process personal data in the context of article/abstract submissions for the purpose of publication of cutting edge research in the field of radiology.
We process personal data in the context of our educational content to properly award credit and provide evidence to third parties of awarded credit.
We process personal data of participants to our events for the purpose of organizing those events.
We process personal data in the context of marketing activities for the purposes of marketing our services and of communicating with our members and customers.
We process personal data of our members and customers to better discern and serve their needs and improve our products and services.
We process personal data in the context of videos and photos that we maintain, for the purposes of informing our members and the public about our activities.
We process personal data collected through cookies placed by our website to support the operation of our website and to analyze the traffic patterns on our site so as to provide better service to visitors and members. See our Cookies Notice for more information.
We process personal data to maintain professional day to day business operations with our partners and vendors.
We process personal data (images and video) to promote and inform our members and the public about our activities and events.
For archiving purposes according to our internal regulations as a nonprofit membership organization.
We process personal data to comply with laws and enforcement requests, to enforce applicable agreements and policies for our services, to prevent fraud, and to comply with all applicable laws; including tax and other local regulations.
Our policy towards children
Our services are not directed to children.
We do not knowingly collect personal data from children. We may incidentally process personal data of children, for instance where participants to our events travel with family or when images we capture for our gallery of videos are those of conditions suffered by children. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with personal data without their consent, please contact us. If we become aware that a child has registered for our services and has provided us with personal data without the consent of their parent or guardian, we will delete such information from our files.
Disclosures to Third Parties
At times, RSNA engages third party contractors, service providers, and other vendors to help us accomplish our business objectives. There are other circumstances where we are required by law to disclose personal data to third parties such as public bodies or judicial authorities.
We engage with our agents, representatives, contractors, service providers or other third parties for the following services:
authorization of credit card transactions (US based),
order fulfillment (US based),
membership management (US based),
Marketing email and print partners (US based),
Education management partners (US based),
If the engagement involves the transmission of personal data, we require the service provider to treat that data consistent with this Policy. A contract to protect the personal data is executed before any data is disclosed, if that vendor will process personal data of individuals in the EU/EEA on our behalf.
RSNA may also disclose information in special cases when it has a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process; (b) protect and defend our rights or property; (c) enforce the Website Terms and Conditions of Use; or (d) act to protect the interests of our users or others. Occasionally RSNA may be required by law enforcement or judicial authorities to provide personally identifiable information to the appropriate governmental authorities. We will disclose such information upon receipt of a court order or subpoena in cooperation with a law enforcement investigation. RSNA reserves the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we in good faith believe to be unlawful.
Your European Privacy Rights
If you reside or otherwise find yourself in the European Economic Area (EEA), RSNA is committed to process your personal data lawfully and facilitate the exercise of your rights granted by the European General Data Protection regulation (GDPR). You can contact us at any time to discuss your privacy concerns.
Legal basis for data collection and use:
We only collect and use personal data when there is a fair and legal basis for its collection and use, for instance, when the collection of personal data is necessary to become member of the Society, to meet our legitimate interests to send marketing material, to comply with legal obligations or when we have your authorization. See below the legal basis for each collection:
Membership information: necessity to enter into a contract or for the performance of a contract and legitimate interest
Registration to events, conferences and the annual meeting: necessity to enter into or for the performance of a contract. For certain processing of personal data in relation to our events, we rely on legitimate interest (e.g. taking photos during the event) to advance our mission as a membership organization in providing education and information.
Marketing activities: Consent for email marketing; our legitimate interests for marketing conducted other than through email or phone call;
Business information: necessity to enter into a contract or for the performance of a contract
Videos and photos: Legitimate interest for informational and educational activities with consent to use specific images and video
Mobile App: legitimate interest to assist Annual Meeting attendees navigate and organize their meeting experience and consent
Journal submissions: necessity to enter or for the performance of a contract
Information collected automatically: consent
Privacy rights under the European regulation:
Transparency and the right to information: we provide notice to our members, website users and other third parties who interact with us of how we use personal data in our day-to-day activities at the time of collecting personal data, or as soon thereafter as possible. We also publish this privacy notice for a greater transparency.
Right to access, rectification, restriction of processing, erasure, and data portability: if you are based in the EEA we provide you with access to your own personal data. In addition, we will rectify your personal data when it is incorrect or inaccurate, and we will ensure the right to erasure, portability and to restriction of processing when these rights are not incompatible with other legal obligations.
Right to object and withdraw consent at any time: for all marketing materials, you can opt-out anytime, and free of charge. The right to object for other processing activities will be balanced to ensure that it is not incompatible with local regulations or our legitimate interests.
These requests should be submitted as follows:
Opt-out of marketing communications: you can opt-out anytime by following the opt-out instructions in our commercial e-mails or contacting us. You will still continue to receive emails relevant to course registrations or purchases (e.g. registration confirmations or purchase receipts) or necessary to your continued membership in RSNA (e.g. dues notices).
To exercise the rest of your rights: you should send a communication in writing to:
Radiological Society of North America
Attn: Privacy
820 Jorie Boulevard
Suite 200
Oak Brook, Illinois 60523, USA
In order to fulfil this request,we may require you provide us information to verify your identity and specify your request. We will attend to your request in a timely manner within 30 days after receiving your request. If for any reason we need to extend this period of time, we will contact you.
If you are not satisfied with our response,you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority of your habitual residence, place of work or place of the alleged infringement.
International Transfers of Personal Data
If you are located outside the United States and you interact with our website or provide us personal data, then your personal data may be transferred to the United States.
We transfer your personal data to the United States whenever you interact with us.
The US has not sought, nor obtained adequacy status from the European Union. The EU-US Privacy Shield framework obtained an adequacy decision. The level of protection of your personal data is not deemed equivalent to the one in the EU, unless the receiving organization is self-certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield or implements other approved transfer mechanisms. As a not-for-profit organization, we are not able to adhere to the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles, nor implement other transfer mechanisms.
We transfer your personal data on the basis of the derogations in Article 49 GDPR, particularly:
Necessity to enter and for the performance of a contract for registration information to participate to our events; for processing personal data of our members to maintain their relationship with our organization, provide them services including when they log in to their member accounts; and also for processing personal data for online and offline courses.
Explicit consent, for newsletter subscribers and certain processing in relation to organizing events - such as storing photos, and marketing activities;
As for safeguards to your personal data, we directly apply the GDPR provisions to your personal data. As a matter of principle, we do not engage in any onward transfers regarding your data, beyond the access that our processors have to your data. We select carefully our processors and we require that provide equivalent safeguard mechanisms.
Data Security
RSNA is committed to the security, confidentiality and integrity principle. We take commercially reasonable precautions to keep all information obtained from our members, conference participants, app users and online visitors secure against unauthorized access and use and we periodically review our security measures.
Security measures:
We use identification and authentication processes to insure that access to PII is limited to RSNA employees who require it. Offsite access to sensitive information requires the use of a VPN. When compiling statistics, we anonymize member data and report on aggregate measures. We employ encryption technology to protect data at rest and in transit.
You should be aware, however, that “perfect security” does not exist on the Internet, and third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications.
This site contains links to other sites. While RSNA strives to link only to sites that share our high standards and respect for privacy, RSNA is not responsible for the privacy practices employed by other sites.
RSNA MAKES NO CLAIMS, PROMISES OR GUARANTEES ABOUT THE ACCURACY, COMPLETENESS OR ADEQUACY OF THE CONTENTS OF ITS SITE, AND EXPRESSLY DISCLAIMS LIABILITY FOR ERRORS AND OMISSIONS IN THE CONTENTS OF THIS SITE. NO WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, IMPLIED, EXPRESSED OR STATUTORY, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF NON-INFRINGEMENT, TITLE, MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND FREEDOM FROM COMPUTER VIRUS, IS GIVEN WITH RESPECT TO THE CONTENTS OF THIS WEBSITE OR ITS HYPERLINKS TO OTHER INTERNET RESOURCES. REFERENCE IN THIS WEBSITE TO ANY SPECIFIC COMMERCIAL PRODUCTS, PROCESSES OR SERVICES, OR THE USE OF ANY TRADE, FIRM OR CORPORATION NAME IS FOR THE INFORMATION AND CONVENIENCE OF THE PUBLIC AND DOES NOT CONSTITUTE ENDORSEMENT OR RECOMMENDATION BY RSNA.
Retention Periods
RSNA applies the storage limitation principle in order to retain personal data in our records only for the length of time required to fulfill the purpose for which the data was collected.
According to our retention policy
We only keep personal data in our records as long as they are necessary for the purposes they have been processed. The retention period depends on the context in which we process data, for instance:
3 years: complaints involving active members
7 years: CME activity data, contracts (after completion)
Permanent: membership application, journal article copyright transfer agreements. Only this information is stored permanently for archiving purposes according to our internal regulations.
Changes to this Policy
We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. We will duly inform you of any changes.
RSNA may occasionally update this privacy statement and other statements referenced by it as new services and programs are introduced.
These changes will be notified to you via an email communication and/or by placing a prominent notice on the Site. The time stamp you see on the policy will indicate the last date it was revised.
